TextSink. Four voices. One truth.
Built on Gemma 4 and Fireworks AI, for the
AMD Developer Hackathon.
One video. Four voices. A formal narrator, a deadpan
cynic, a developer who's seen things, and your favorite
neighbor. This is TextSink. And every word you're seeing
was written live by Gemma 4, about the actual
competition clips.
Under the hood, it's the official Track 2 contract.
Tasks in, captions out, fully containerized.
The container probes its model access, grounds every clip
in scene facts, drafts three captions per style, judges
its own drafts, and ships the winner.
And if grounding ever comes back empty, it refuses
to caption blind. An empty caption is structurally impossible.
Four styles isn't one prompt with four adjectives.
Broadcast precision. Deadpan, scale mismatch irony.
A developer culture metaphor built from what's actually on
screen. And warm, everyday relatability.
An AI judge can blind sort these.
That's the tone score.
Then we kept going. The same grounding becomes real
closed captions. A timed subtitle track you can toggle,
with one consistent voice across the whole clip.
A tiny orange predator prepares for total world domination.
The menace is closing in.
Send help.
And because one voice is a monologue: The Hecklers.
Two different models, Gemma 4 versus GPT-OSS, watch the
clip and argue about it, turn by turn.
Every line generated live. It's a strawberry milkshake apocalypse,
Gus! Apocalypse? It's just sunset, not your dairy fantasy.
And when the code reviewer meets the vibe coder:
touch grass, Lint, before your soul segfaults.
The models wrote every word.
Gemma grounds it. Writes it.
Argues it. Judges it. And last night, it trained
its own captioner on the drafts it judged best.
TextSink. Four voices. One truth.
TextSink. Thanks to AMD, Fireworks AI, Google DeepMind's Gemma,
and lablab.ai. Find us on GitHub.